MARK WARNEKE

RESUME

OBJECTIVE

Ever considered looking for a German engineer? I am an undergraduate looking for a job as a junior software developer in an English-speaking country. I want to improve my software engineering skills and enhance my proficiency in the English language.

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am an open-minded, highly motivated, self thought programmer. In addition, I am a trained management assistant with 3 years of work experience as a sales person. During my university education I gathered 2 years of experience as a software developer in different work environments. I am currently working at Porsche AG in Germany and will finish my Bachelor of Science in business informatics at the University of Applied Science Münster (Germany) at the end of September 2016.

EXPERIENCE

INTERNSHIP IT-SERVICE-MANAGEMENT DR. ING. H. C. F. PORSCHE AG

04/2016 - today

Working as an assistant IT project manager for the production services of the new electric car at Porsche Germany. I am currently writing my bachelor thesis about the change management process for IT services. I am implementing the ITIL processes into the existing IT service management using the atlassian software bundle jira and confluence.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

RATIODATA IT-LÖSUNGEN & SERVICES GMBH

05/2015 - 04/2016

Developed a java based scan application <u>Scan2bank21</u> for Ricoh multi-function printer at a financial service provider. The embedded software handles the transfer of banking manuscripts into the central-archive bank21 of the Fiducia & GAD IT AG. The application uses a SOAP web service for secure authentication and configuration of the application. It handles basic image processing using the java Catalano Framework. My work included the requirements engineering, design, development, testing, debugging and interface design of the application, as well as training new developers. I implemented a basic continuous delivery system using an ant. The development process was the agile method scrum.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

VECTRON SYSTEMS AG

11/2014 - 05/2015

Designed and implemented the merge of Google Analytic data into the data warehouse-system using Java. Developed a basic customer relationship management system for sales and administrative staff, using PHP and MySQL. The web application implemented the CSS framework Bootstrap and took use of some basic AJAX and jQuery DOM manipulaiton.

IT MANAGEMENT ASSISTANT

ETE-DATENTECHNIK GMBH

07/2012 - 09/2013

Built up a small client base and was responsible for IT projects in the sales department. The project were in the fields: network solutions, security solutions, communications (VOIP) and server and storage projects. Developed a basic sales forecast using excel and VBA. Developed a simple controlling application for sales-staff phone calls, using an ETL process to gather information from the VOIP-Server, using shell scripts, Excel and simple VBA.

EDUCATION	
10/2013 - today	STUDENT - BUSINESS INFORMATICS (B.SC.) UNIVERSITY OF APPLIED SCIENCES MÜNSTER
08/2010 - 07/2012	APPRENTICESHIP - IT MANAGEMENT ASSISTANT ETE-DATENTECHNIK GMBH
08/2008 - 08/2010	APPRENTICESHIP - ASSISTANT IN BUSINESS INFORMATICS BBS AM POSTGRABEN
OTHER PROJECTS	
11/2014 - today	STUDENT MANAGEMENT CONSULTANCY KREAKTIV E.V UNIVERSITY OF APPLIED SCIENCES MÜNSTER
	Ressort IT Project manager: "development of a web application" (Sensà Einrichtungshaus) Project manager: "development of a website" (KREAKTIV e.V.)
2014 - today	WEB & APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT STUDENT PROJECTS
	AngularJS1 WebApplication with .NET MVC back-end
	Android Application budget management using Java EE back-end
	Secure message API (End-to-End REST Service) using Ruby on Rails
06/2014 - 08/2014	WEB DEVELOPMENT SELF-EMPLOYED
	Basic reporting system for car service station using PHP and MS SQL Photography Website, developed basic CMS with CakePHP
OKILLO	
SKILLS IT SKILLS	Drafficiant in Java To C# Not DID LTML CCC (Dranga coccurs)
II SKILLS	Proficient in Java, Java EE, C#, .Net, PHP, HTML, CSS (Preprocessors), JavaScript, AngularJS, Android, SQL, Mac, Linux, Windows, Windows Server, Git, Maven, Ant, Graddle, Grunt, Gulp, Microsoft Office
	Familiar with Ruby-on-Rails, Go and Python, TypeScript, AJAX, AngularJS2, NodeJs, through student projects and online courses
CERTIFICATES	VMware VSP Sales Professional 5 (06/2013), IBM Certified Specialist System x Sales V6 (07/2012), Cisco SMB Specialisation for Account Managers (06/2011)
LANGUAGE	English (Good, B2 CEF); German (native)
OTHERS	Very keen on learning new skills and experiences
	Able to work independently on tasks
	Other a interest in mountable plants and be suited to the state of

Strong interest in new technologies and how they function